Episode 9
에피소드 9
Madam, he has arrived.
부인, 그가 도착했어요.
Hello, madam.
안녕하세요, 부인.
I am currently underemployed.
저는 지금 불완전 취업 상태입니다.
Don't mind what I said before.
내가 전에 말한 것은 신경쓰지 마세요 .
There might be a conflict with Jong Ye-ran...
종예란과 갈등이 생길지도 ..
But I still...
하지만 난 아직도...
Daughter of the Hwa family...
화씨 가문의 딸...
And my father is an assistant here.
그리고 우리 아버지는 여기서 조수예요.
If you keep working here...
여기서 계속 일하면...
You will profit.
당신은 이익을 얻을 것입니다.
Because I took care of my wife...
내가 부인을 돌보게 되었기 때문에 ...
Madam, you are my only master.
부인은 나의 유일한 주인입니다.
good!
좋은!
I said there was hope...
희망이 있다고 했는데...
And I was right.
그리고 내가 옳았다.
Please let me know if you need help.
도움이 필요하면 알려주세요 .
There is a lot for you to do...
당신이 할 일이 많이 있습니다 ...
now.
지금.
- Kuiju - Yes!
- 쿠이주 - 예!
help.
도와주세요.
I'm going.
나는 간다.
Go ahead and try it.
어서 해봐요.
Why do you look at me like that?
왜 나를 그렇게 보는 거죠?
I heard.
나는 들었다.
What did you hear?
무엇을 들었나요?
Just don't push...
그냥 밀지 마세요...
It's the cost of food and clothes, ma'am.
음식 과 옷에 대한 비용입니다 부인..
As well as moving all employees...
뿐만 아니라 모든 직원을 이동합니다 ...
A person who cleans his area.
자기 지역을 청소하는 사람.
Chief of security, don't be stupid.
경호원장, 바보같은 소리 하지 마세요.
I don't dare...
감히 그러지 못해요...
Wants to cut down on his expenses.
그의 비용을 줄이고 싶어합니다.
This is your command.
이것이 당신의 명령입니다.
Did you tell them to move all the employees?
직원을 모두 옮기라고 했나 ?
Don't think I don't know...
내가 모른다고 생각하지 마세요...
He never gave any such instructions.
그는 그런 지시를 한 적이 없습니다.
As a result, women...
그 결과 여자들은...
Everyone is busy.
다들 바빠요.
It's not my fault.
내 잘못이 아니야.
Even without giving these instructions...
이런 지시를 내리지 않아도...
subordinates and subordinates...
부하들 과 부하들...
I came here to ask for a change.
바꿔달라고 하러 왔습니다.
It's difficult to please everyone.
모든 사람을 만족시키는 것은 어렵습니다.
I have no choice but to follow their will.
나는 그들의 뜻을 따를 수 밖에 없습니다.
After all, you are not against it.
결국, 당신은 반대하지 않습니다.
Don't use him as an excuse.
그를 핑계로 삼지 마십시오.
You misunderstood.
당신은 오해했습니다.
I wouldn't dare.
나는 감히하지 않을 것입니다.
You can cut costs , but don't overdo it.
비용을 줄일 수는 있지만 과용하지 마십시오.
Follow the rules.
규칙을 따르세요.
If you know this, you take responsibility.
이 사실을 알면 책임을 집니다 .
But if you listen...
하지만 들어보면...
You treat women rudely...
당신은 여자를 무례하게 대합니다 ...
I won't be rude to you.
나는 당신에게 예의를 갖추지 않을 것입니다.
Remember, I'm in charge of security...
기억해, 나는 경비를 담당하고 있어...
In this area.
이 지역에서.
great.
좋아요.
approval.
승인.
For those who want to go...
가자고 하시는 분들을 위해 ...
No need to move again.
다시 이동할 필요가 없습니다.
We do not need to imprison unfaithful people .
우리는 불충실한 사람들을 가둘 필요가 없습니다 .
of.
의.
Don't forget...
잊지 마요...
To command your people.
주의 백성에게 명령을 내리려 함이니라
great.
좋아요.
am...
이다...
Is he really serious?
그 사람 정말 진심이야?
I'm ready, ma'am.
준비됐어요, 부인.
Isn’t this kind of cool?
이거 좀 멋지지 않나요?
This isn't the first time...
이번이 처음이 아니다...
I met that woman.
나는 그 여인을 만났습니다.
Miss has just recovered.
Miss가 방금 회복되었습니다.
So a luxurious appearance will bring good luck.
그래서 호화로운 외모는 행운을 가져올 것입니다.
great.
좋아요.
Is the cart ready?
카트는 준비됐나요?
We don't need to get out...
우리는 나갈 필요가 없습니다 ...
And it pays, right?
그리고 돈을 내는 거죠, 그렇죠?
I confirm.
내가 확인합니다.
Madam, stop.
부인, 그만하세요.
Your brother sent it to you, right?
형이 보낸 거 맞죠?
I told him many times...
나는 그에게 여러 번 말했습니다 ...
But he doesn't want to hear it.
하지만 그는 그것을 듣고 싶어하지 않습니다.
He still buys me jewelry.
그는 아직도 나에게 보석을 사준다.
All of this puts a strain on running.
이 모든 것이 달리기에 부담이 됩니다 .
Next time he sends more items...
다음에 그 사람이 더 많은 물건을 보내면 ...
I can keep pushing.
계속 밀어붙일 수 있어요.
Please tell me I'm not interested in that.
나는 그런 것에는 관심이 없다고 말해주세요 .
This is no ordinary gem.
이것은 평범한 보석이 아닙니다.
Finally my brother learned something.
마침내 내 동생이 뭔가를 배웠습니다.
He discovered something special.
그는 뭔가 특별한 것을 발견했습니다.
Madam, be careful.
부인, 조심하세요.
This knife is small...
이 칼은 작아요..
But it's very sharp.
하지만 매우 날카롭습니다.
How sharp is it?
얼마나 날카로운가?
Tell it to your brother...
형한테 전해줘...
I really like this.
나는 이것을 정말로 좋아한다.
I didn't mean to do that.
그럴 생각은 없었어요.
wake up. Don't be too polite.
깨우다. 너무 예의바르게 행동하지 마세요.
Tell me please...
말해 주세요...
How do I make this into a bracelet again?
이걸 어떻게 다시 팔찌로 만들 수 있나요?
This is very useful for self-defense.
이는 자기 방어에 매우 유용합니다.
I have nothing...
나는 아무것도 없다 ...
You can watch it here.
여기에서 시청할 수 있습니다.
I want to go to Jong Park...
종공원 가고싶다...
We need a security guard.
경비원이 필요해요.
Can you take me there?
나를 거기로 데려다 줄 수 있어?
good.
좋은.
Young boys are obedient.
어린 소년들은 순종적입니다.
Miss, shouldn't you be there?
아가씨, 거기 있어야 하지 않나요?
I was invited here.
나는 여기에 초대되었습니다.
It's daytime now.
지금은 낮이에요.
I don't think anyone would dare...
감히 누구도 감히 할 수 없을 것 같은데...
want to trap me
나를 함정에 빠뜨리고 싶어
are you okay. We will go alone.
괜찮아요. 우리는 혼자 갈 거예요.
Coincidentally, my daughter-in-law.
공교롭게도 며느리.
What is my destiny?
내 운명은 무엇인가.
I want to see my mom by chance.
우연히 엄마를 보고 싶어요.
Let's go together.
함께 가자.
Has your injury healed?
부상은 치료됐나요?
The length of a day at Jong Residence...
종 레지던스에서의 하루의 길이...
I didn't have time to ask more...
더 물어볼 시간이 없었는데 ...
Because my senior wants to see it.
선배가 보고 싶어하니까.
At that time, you asked a detailed question ...
그때 자세히 질문하셨는데 ..
And I'm fine now.
그리고 나는 지금 괜찮아요.
I think you're still angry.
내 생각엔 당신이 아직도 화가 난 것 같아요.
You still think...
당신은 여전히 ​​​​생각합니다 ...
I've been testing you all this time?
내가 그동안 널 시험했다고?
You must be joking.
농담하는 게 틀림없어요.
I dare not think so.
나는 감히 그렇게 생각하지 않는다.
Don't you dare think that...
감히 그렇게 생각하지 마세요...
But aren't you angry?
그런데 당신은 화나지 않았나요?
To be clear...
확실히 말씀드리자면...
I will never second-guess your actions again.
다시는 당신의 행동에 대해 추측하지 않겠습니다 .
can you forgive me
나를 용서 해줄수 있겠 니?
why?
왜?
Are you talking to me?
나와 대화하고 있니?
Who else?
그밖에 누가?
All your thoughts must have meaning.
당신의 모든 생각은 의미가 있어야 합니다.
So there’s no guessing, right?
그럼 추측은 없겠죠?
Just forget it. There will be times like that.
그냥 잊어 버리세요. 그럴 때가 있을 겁니다.
I remembered what you said last time...
저번에 하신 말씀이 생각났는데 ...
And I thought that was very reasonable.
그리고 그것은 매우 합리적이라고 생각했습니다.
Sekali Ragi.
세칼리 라기.
Didn’t you promise not to make any more guesses ?
더 이상의 추측은 하지 않겠다고 약속하지 않았나요 ?
Forgive me for what I didn't know...
몰랐던 것을 용서하세요...
But can you tell what's wrong with me?
그런데 나한테 무슨 문제가 있는지 알 수 있을까?
I said I would stop making assumptions about you.
나는 당신에 대한 추측을 중단하겠다고 말했습니다.
So you don't need to be too careful .
그러니 너무 조심할 필요는 없습니다 .
I am a fool If I believe you
나는 바보입니다 당신을 믿으면
You said that a person lives only once.
사람의 인생은 한번뿐이라고 말씀하셨는데요 .
Therefore, it is not worth risking your life for.
그러므로 목숨을 걸고 할 가치가 없습니다 .
We'll have to think about this in the future.
앞으로는 이것에 대해 생각해야합니다 .
You're threatening my life?
내 생명을 위협한다고요?
I mean, you...
내 말은, 당신은 ...
Hello, madam.
안녕하세요, 부인.
Please sit next to me.
내 옆에 앉으세요.
Yes ma'am.
네 부인.
You are so bad.
당신은 정말 나쁘다.
Yelan is skilled in martial arts.
옐란은 무술에 능숙합니다 .
There is no need to protect him from arrows.
그를 화살로부터 보호할 필요는 없습니다 .
It hurts for a long time...
오랫동안 아프게 만드네요...
And make me worry about you...
그리고 내가 당신을 걱정하게 만드세요...
At this age.
이 나이에.
The lady is right.
부인 말이 맞아요.
I feel really bad and am in too much of a hurry.
나는 정말 나쁘고 너무 서두르고 있습니다.
Thank you for your consideration.
배려해 주셔서 감사합니다.
I won't do it again.
다시는 안 할 거예요.
Look how skinny you are.
당신이 얼마나 마른 지보세요.
I used to think you were so weak.
나는 당신이 너무 약하다고 생각하곤 했어요.
Now you are thin.
이제 당신은 말랐습니다.
How do you want to give birth?
어떻게 낳고 싶나요 ?
membrane.
막.
Mom is picky.
엄마는 까다 롭습니다.
I have been here for a long time.
나는 오랫동안 여기에 있었습니다.
But I feel like my mom can't see me.
그런데 엄마가 나를 보지 못하는 것 같아요 .
How dare you say that?
감히 그런 말을 합니까?
You are not married yet.
당신은 아직 결혼하지 않았습니다.
Then Yellen would be better...
그럼 옐런이 좋겠다...
To have grandchildren.
손자를 가지려고.
I heard they boil noodles...
국수를 끓인다고 들었는데...
For his birthday.
그의 생일을 위해.
I just cook as usual.
저는 그냥 평소대로 요리해요.
Intention matters.
의도가 중요합니다.
Spoiled little girls like you are rare.
너처럼 버릇없는 어린 소녀는 드물다 .
I want to go into the kitchen...
부엌에 들어가고 싶어...
And please cook noodles for him.
그리고 그를 위해 국수를 요리해 주세요.
You've been sick for a long time...
오랫동안 아프셨군요...
But why aren't you saying anything to me ?
그런데 왜 나한테 아무 말도 안 해 ?
I am really worried...
나는 정말 걱정을하고 있습니다...
Almost sent a doctor .
거의 의사를 보냈어요 .
Mom, I heard you were in a coma for 5 days...
엄마, 5일 동안 혼수상태에 계셨다고 들었어요 ...
And I am very worried.
그리고 매우 걱정됩니다.
So he told me to bring Dr. Wu here.
그래서 그는 우 박사를 여기로 데려오라고 말했습니다.
Please forgive. That won't happen next time.
용서 해줘. 다음에는 그런 일이 일어나지 않을 것입니다.
Next time?
다음번?
Don't you think I've lived too long ?
내가 너무 오래 살았다고 생각 하지 않나요?
I said wrong. Please forgive.
내가 잘못 말했다. 용서 해줘.
Madam, don't be angry.
부인, 화내지 마세요.
I shouldn't be angry.
나는 화를 내면 안 된다.
ma'am.
부인.
I will remember everything you told me.
나는 당신이 나에게 말한 모든 것을 기억할 것입니다.
How are you.
잘 지내세요.
Your wife is the same.
부인도 똑같습니다.
It's late, so we have to go now.
시간이 늦었으니 지금 가봐야 해요.
I need to rest early.
일찍 쉬어야 해요.
I will definitely visit next time .
다음에 꼭 방문 하겠습니다 .
OK. Be careful on your way.
괜찮은. 가는 길에 조심하세요.
great.
좋아요.
Mom, it's late.
엄마, 늦었어요.
So I won't bother you any more.
그러니 더 이상 당신을 괴롭히지 않겠습니다.
go away.
저리 가요.
Sister-in-law.
시누이.
Hua Chen.
화첸.
What are you doing
뭐하세요
It is not okay for men and women to touch each other.
남자 와 여자가 ​​서로 만지는 것은 좋지 않습니다 .
Needless to say, I am your sister-in-law.
말할 것도 없이 나는 당신의 처제입니다.
Are you trying to do something bad to me?
나한테 나쁜 짓을 하려는 거야?
I called you a few times ago.
몇 번 전에 전화를 했어요.
But you pretend not to hear it.
그런데 넌 못 들은 척 하잖아.
Why are you blaming me now ?
왜 지금 나를 비난하는 건가요 ?
Did you call me?
나한테 전화했어?
It reminds me of Tuan Yelan.
투안 옐란(Tuan Yelan)이 생각난다.
So I hurried home but didn't hear anything.
그래서 서둘러 집에 갔지만 듣지 못했습니다.
Didn't you file your divorce papers a few days ago?
며칠 전에 이혼 서류를 제출하지 않았나요 ?
Why are you still using him as an excuse?
왜 아직도 그를 핑계로 삼는 걸까요 ?
The teacher is very busy.
선생님은 매우 바빠요.
Don't disturb me...
방해하면 안 되는데...
To someone else's family problems.
다른 사람의 가족 문제에.
What's going on today?
오늘 무슨 일 있어?
Like someone made you angry .
누군가가 당신을 화나게 한 것처럼 .
Sir, if you have nothing more to say...
선생님, 더 하실 말씀 없으시면 ...
i want to go now
나는 지금 가고 싶다
Let me finish my speech, shall we ?
내 연설을 마치도록 하지요 ?
What I wanted to say earlier is...
앞서 제가 말하고자 했던 것은...
Cherishing your life is...
자신의 삶을 소중히 여기는 것은...
If you truly want me to cherish my life...
진심으로 내 생명을 소중히 여기길 바란다면...
You shouldn't bother me here .
여기서 나를 귀찮게 해서는 안 됩니다 .
There are a lot of people in Zong Park.
종공원에는 ​​사람이 많아요.
Have you ever thought...
생각해 본 적 있니...
My condition...
내 상태는...
When others see us?
다른 사람들이 우리를 볼 때?
No one dares talk about us.
아무도 감히 우리에 대해 이야기하지 않습니다.
No one will say anything about you.
아무도 당신에 대해 아무 말도하지 않을 것입니다.
But what about me?
하지만 나는 어떻습니까?
I am no longer loved by Tuan Yelan.
나는 더 이상 Tuan Yelan의 사랑을 받지 않습니다.
My father is getting older too.
아버지도 늙어가고 계시네요.
My brother got nothing.
내 동생은 아무것도 얻지 못했습니다.
As a woman, I feel lonely and helpless...
여자로서 외롭고 무력한데...
And of course...
그리고 물론...
You won't understand my struggles.
당신은 내 어려움을 이해하지 못할 것입니다.
The way you describe your situation is ...
당신의 상황을 설명하는 방식은 ...
Do you still think I'm testing you ?
아직도 내가 널 시험하고 있다고 생각해 ?
Just forget it.
그냥 잊어 버리세요.
Madam, why are you so brave today?
부인, 오늘 왜 그렇게 용감하신가요?
He is our master.
그는 우리의 주인입니다.
Of course I know.
당연히 알지.
Because that person is our master...
그 사람이 우리 주인이니까...
If you say that, he will know now...
그렇게 말해야 그 사람도 이제 알겠지...
He doesn't need to use me...
그 사람은 나를 이용할 필요가 없어...
To oppress my family.
내 가족을 억압하려고요.
Let's get out of here quickly.
빨리 여기서 나가자.
why?
왜?
I was angry that he was testing me.
나는 그가 나를 시험한 것에 화가 났다.
So my tone of voice was harsh.
그래서 내 말투가 거칠었다.
Maybe when he realizes, he will punish me.
아마 그 사람이 깨달으면 나를 처벌할 거예요 .
fast.
빠른.
This is new.
이것은 새로운 것입니다.
Lady, don't forget your father's instructions.
아가씨, 아버지의 지시를 잊지 마세요.
Don't interfere in other people's business.
다른 사람의 일 에 간섭하지 마십시오 .
You don't need to remind me.
나에게 상기시켜 줄 필요는 없습니다.
When I saw Qian today...
오늘 Qian을 보니...
He didn't care about Yellen.
그는 옐런에 대해 관심이 없었습니다.
Maybe you're still angry.
어쩌면 당신은 여전히 ​​화가 났을 수도 있습니다.
then...
그렇다면...
He will complain.
그는 불평할 것이다.
Look at the way I talk about Yellen today ...
오늘 내가 옐런에 대해 말하는 방식을 보시죠 ...
But he didn't want to talk about Yelan .
하지만 그는 옐란에 대해서는 이야기하고 싶지 않았습니다 .
Would you like to meet Ms. Yellen?
옐런 씨를 만나보실래요?
It's unreasonable...
불합리해요...
Yelan ignored Qian.
Yelan은 Qian을 무시했습니다.
But I am old.
하지만 나는 나이가 많습니다.
They didn't ask me for help.
그들은 나에게 도움을 요청하지 않았습니다.
If I interfere in their business...
내가 그들의 일에 간섭한다면...
I just harass them.
나는 단지 그들을 괴롭힐 뿐입니다.
ma'am.
부인.
Tuan Yelan's parents died when he was young.
Tuan Yelan의 부모는 어렸을 때 사망했습니다.
Mr. and Mrs....
씨와 부인....
serve him...
그를 섬기다...
From a young age, like your own child.
어렸을 때부터 자기 자식처럼 .
He won't think of you as a troublemaker.
그는 당신을 말썽꾼으로 생각하지 않을 것입니다 .
After all, as long as they are still husband and wife...
결국, 그들이 여전히 남편과 아내인 한...
They will be together again.
그들은 다시 함께하게 될 것입니다.
Qian is a smart girl...
Qian은 똑똑한 소녀입니다 ...
but...
하지만...
sadly.
슬프게도.
Mom, it's late.
엄마, 늦었어요.
So I won't bother you any more.
그러니 더 이상 당신을 괴롭히지 않겠습니다.
ma'am.
부인.
why?
왜?
naught.
아무것도 아님.
Maybe I'm thinking too much.
어쩌면 내가 너무 많이 생각하고 있는 것일 수도 있다.
I'm full. Clean the table.
나는 전체 해요. 테이블을 청소하세요.
Okay, ma'am.
좋아요, 부인.
ma'am.
부인.
I checked the store today...
오늘 매장을 확인해 보니..
You can see all times and times, play chess, and write utensils...
고금도 보이고 체스도 있고 필기구도 있고...
The one Mr. Yelan gave me is very dusty.
옐란 씨가 준 것은 먼지가 많습니다.
Madame always makes fun of things like that without doing anything about it.
마담은 아무것도 하지 않으면 서 항상 그런 것을 놀립니다 .
What should I bring to the lady...
아줌마한테 뭘 가져가야 하나 ...
Want to utilize your time?
시간을 활용하려고?
Qianzhi.
Qianzhi.
How do you think I will treat Jong Ye-ran...
내가 종예란을 어떻게 대할 것 같나 ...
Before I get married?
나 결혼하기 전에?
are you okay. You can answer freely.
괜찮아. 자유롭게 답변하시면 됩니다.
Madam, I love you so much, sir.
부인, 정말 사랑해요 선생님.
He likes chess.
그는 체스를 좋아합니다.
So you learned how to play from many teachers .
그래서 당신은 많은 선생님들로부터 노는 법을 배웠습니다 .
He likes listening to guqin's music.
그는 guqin의 음악을 듣는 것을 좋아합니다.
So you do everything to master it.
그래서 당신은 그것을 마스터하기 위해 모든 것을합니다.
He appreciates beautiful handwriting.
그는 아름다운 손글씨를 높이 평가합니다.
So I still want to practice...
그래서 아직도 연습하고 싶은데...
It doesn't matter whether the weather is hot or cold.
날씨가 덥든 춥든 상관없습니다.
If you praise...
칭찬하면..
Woman's drawing skills...
여자 그림 실력..
Your wife is going to visit her...
부인이 그 여자를 방문할 거예요...
meet...
만나다...
And learn from him.
그리고 그에게서 배우세요.
great.
좋아요.
I never learned anything like that...
난 그런거 하나도 배운적 없는데...
Because I like it.
왜냐면 내가 그걸 좋아 하니까.
So now I don't want to touch it anymore.
그래서 이제는 더 이상 만지고 싶지 않습니다.
Maybe you're a little angry.
어쩌면 당신은 조금 화가 났을 수도 있습니다.
Do you want to apologize to that person?
그 사람에게 사과하고 싶나요?
I hope he gets angry...
그 사람이 화났으면 좋겠다...
And please remember my mistakes.
그리고 내 실수를 기억해 주세요.
I hope...
나는 희망...
He divorced me...
그 사람이 나랑 이혼했어...
So there's no need to think...
그러니 생각할 필요도 없지...
How do I force him?
어떻게 그에게 강요하나요?
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
ma'am.
부인.
Hua Residence's variety has arrived.
Hua Residence의 다양이 왔습니다.
And Maid Hua said she asked...
그리고 Maid Hua가 물었다고 하더군요...
The lady is coming tomorrow.
아주머니가 내일 오세요.
I have to go there.
나는 거기에 가야 한다.
Kian.
키안.
Qian, do you like the jewelry you sent me?
Qian, 나에게 보낸 보석은 마음에 드나요 ?
of.
의.
So why not use it?
그럼 왜 그것을 사용하지 않습니까?
Jewelry my brother bought me...
내 동생이 사준 보석 ..
All of them are unique and beautiful.
그들 모두는 독특하고 아름답습니다.
Matches your beauty...
당신의 아름다움과 일치합니다 ...
Then you will surpass others.
그러면 당신은 다른 사람들을 능가할 것입니다.
The emerald my brother bought me ...
형이 사준 에메랄드 ...
i know. Look at.
알아요. 바라보다.
This is from my brother. I wear it.
이건 내 동생이 보낸 거야. 나는 그것을 입는다.
Brother, can I give you this bracelet?
형님, 이 팔찌 주세요?
Calm down and talk to him.
진정하고 그와 이야기하십시오.
don't worry.
걱정 하지마.
do not be angry.
화 내지 마.
nurse.
유모.
membrane.
막.
Mom son...
엄마 아들...
I haven't seen you for a long time.
나는 당신을 오랫동안 보지 못했습니다.
Why do you look thin?
왜 날씬해 보이나요?
Did your master treat you badly?
주인님이 당신을 나쁘게 대했나요?
Just talk.
그냥 얘기하세요.
I was wrong about that.
나는 그에 대해 틀렸다.
A cruel and heartless man.
잔인 하고 무정한 남자.
Honey, please let me sit down first.
여보, 먼저 앉게 해주세요.
sit down.
앉아.
Kian.
키안.
Was it cured?
치료됐나요?
I like it.
내가 좋아입니다.
I heard...
들었어...
Are you asking for a divorce?
이혼을 요구하는 거야?
- yes. - Why did you do that?
- 예. - 왜 그런 짓을 한거야?
You are no longer a slave.
당신은 더 이상 노예가 아닙니다.
But you are still stubborn.
하지만 당신은 여전히 ​​완고합니다.
Why is my father angry at me without asking why?
왜 아버지는 이유도 묻지 않고 나에게 화를 내시는 걸까요?
Why else?
이유는 또 무엇입니까?
Because daddy spoils you so much.
아빠가 널 너무 망치니까.
- Honey... - That's why you're so stubborn.
- 여보... - 그래서 고집이 센 거야.
to!
에게!
Qian is still young.
Qian은 아직 어리다.
Be patient with him.
그에게 인내심을 가지십시오.
drinking water.
식수.
Drink water and stay calm.
물을 마시고 침착함을 유지하세요.
Kian.
키안.
This time Tuan Yelan made a mistake.
이번에는 Tuan Yelan이 실수를 했습니다.
But you really want to marry that person.
하지만 당신은 정말로 그 사람과 결혼하고 싶어합니다.
right?
오른쪽?
Why are you still stubborn?
왜 아직도 완고합니까?
The secret to maintaining a marriage is ...
결혼생활을 유지하는 비결은 ..
If you want to stay here for a while...
한동안 여기에 머물고 싶다면 ...
Mom and Dad get scolded too...
엄마아빠도 혼나고..
Without asking why.
이유를 묻지 않고.
Now it's the same.
이제는 동일합니다.
Mom and Dad think of me as a child...
엄마아빠는 나를 어린아이로 생각하는데...
Or as the wife of a servant?
아니면 종 거주지의 부인으로서 ?
It has to be first.
첫 번째 여야합니다.
My sister thinks it's okay to divorce.
내 동생의 생각에는 이혼해도 좋은 것 같다.
It's so beautiful...
너무 아름다워요...
And there are many people like you.
그리고 당신 같은 사람도 많아요.
You shouldn't stay there to be treated badly.
나쁜 대우를 받기 위해 거기 머물러서는 안됩니다 .
shut up.
입 다물어.
You are not qualified to speak!
당신은 말할 자격이 없습니다!
You just know how to play.
당신은 노는 법만 알죠.
If you have a stronger sense of responsibility...
책임감이 더 강하다면..
Dad doesn't have to be hard...
아빠는 힘들지 않아도 돼...
For your family!
가족을 위해!
I never thought this would happen if my dad found out ...
아빠가 알면 이렇게 될 줄이야...
Dad would be better off without a son!
아빠는 아들이 없는 게 낫겠어요!
to.
에게.
Dad, tell me.
아빠, 말해 보세요.
What does your dad work hard for?
아빠는 무엇을 위해 열심히 일하시나요?
Dad wants to do that...
아빠가 그러고 싶어...
Seize sole power in a servant's residence...
종 거주지에서 단독 권력을 쥐다 ...
Or do you want your family to be safe and happy?
아니면 우리 가족이 안전하고 행복하기를 바라시나요?
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
I never understood my father's feelings.
나는 아버지의 마음을 결코 이해하지 못했습니다.
So I want to listen to what Dad says.
그래서 아빠 말을 듣고 싶어요.
What is the intention behind that question?
그 질문 뒤에 숨겨진 의도는 무엇입니까?
Because dad didn't answer...
아빠가 대답을 안해서...
Let's see.
어디 보자.
I think that's what dad wants...
내 생각엔 아빠가 원하는 것 같아...
Aren't you in power in your servant's residence?
종 거주지에서 권력을 잡고 있지 않습니까?
Dad said he did everything for this family.
아빠는 이 가족을 위해 모든 일을 했다고 말씀하셨어요 .
But the father did not teach his son well.
하지만 아버지는 아들을 잘 가르치지 않으셨는데..
Look at his broken morals.
그의 깨진 도덕을보세요.
Then I saw my son being abused...
그러다가 내 아들이 학대당하는 걸 봤어요 ...
And scolded him for no reason.
그리고 이유 없이 그를 꾸짖었다.
For dad...
아빠를 위해...
Am I just Jong Ye-ran’s wife?
제가 그냥 종예란의 아내인가요?
Qian, you can't talk to your father like that .
퀴안, 그런 식으로 아버지께 얘기하면 안 돼요.
Is there something wrong with what I said ?
내가 말한 내용에 무슨 문제가 있나요 ?
I broke up with Jong Ye-ran...
종예란과 헤어졌어요 ..
And he allowed me to stay there without doing my duty.
그리고 그는 내가 임무를 수행하지 않고 그곳에 머물도록 허락했습니다 .
Why can't I go there?
나는 왜 거기에서 갈 수 없습니까 ?
Should I waste my life there?
거기서 내 인생을 낭비해야 합니까 ?
Don't you...
당신은 그렇지 않습니까 ...
Who wanted to marry him ?
그 사람 과 결혼하고 싶었던 사람이 누구였습니까 ?
Do you regret it now?
지금 후회하시나요?
of.
의.
I want to marry that person ...
그 사람 과 결혼하고 싶어요 ...
Pretending to be his childhood sweetheart .
그의 어린 시절 연인인 척 .
I also drug her to marry me.
나는 또한 그녀에게 나와 결혼하기 위해 약을 먹입니다.
What my father taught me...
아버지가 나에게 가르쳐주신 것..
Ever since I was little...
어렸을 때부터...
That I have to fight for what I want...
내가 원하는 것을 위해 싸워야 한다는 것입니다 ...
No matter what happens.
무슨 일이 있어도.
I heard, I remember...
들었어, 기억나...
And do it.
그리고 그것을 하세요.
But I was young and naive.
하지만 나는 어리고 순진했어요.
I don't know the difference between right and wrong.
나는 옳고 그름의 차이를 모른다 .
I let my emotions control everything.
나는 내 감정이 모든 것을 통제하도록 놔둔다.
Dad knows too.
아빠도 알아요.
But you don't know...
그런데 아빠는 모르시죠...
What did I do wrong?
내가 뭘 잘못했나요?
In my heart, my father always reigns supreme.
내 마음 속에서는 언제나 아버지가 최고로 군림하신다 .
But why didn't my dad stop me?
그런데 왜 아빠는 나를 말리지 않았나요?
While I pretend to be someone else?
내가 다른 사람인 척 하는 동안?
When I wanted to give medicine to Jong Ye-ran...
종예란에게 약을 주고 싶었을 때 ...
Why didn't you tell me...
왜 나한테 말 안 했어...
Women shouldn't be evil?
여자는 사악하면 안 된다고?
parents...
부모...
We need to fix the kids...
아이들을 바로잡아야지...
When they're on the wrong track, right?
그들이 잘못된 길에 있을 때 그렇죠?
Mom might be an ordinary woman...
엄마는 평범한 여자일지도 몰라...
With limited knowledge...
제한된 지식으로...
But dad...
하지만 아빠...
Won't you teach us what is right and what is wrong?
무엇이 옳고 그른지 우리에게 가르쳐 주지 않겠습니까 ?
nurse.
유모.
I don't think Dad will care right now...
아빠는 지금 당장은 신경쓰지 않을 것 같은데...
About what I used to do .
내가 예전에 했던 일에 대해 .
In the end, Dad...
결국 아빠는...
I want to become an assistant.
나는 어시스턴트가 되고 싶다.
Dad didn't care about us at all.
아빠는 우리를 전혀 신경쓰지 않으셨어요.
Kian.
키안.
You are becoming braver.
당신은 점점 더 용감해지고 있습니다.
OK. listen.
괜찮은. 듣다.
If my dad hadn't gotten an assistant job...
아빠가 보조직을 잡지 않았다면 ..
My family...
우리 가족이...
Will I be able to live comfortably?
편안하게 살 수 있을까?
You and your brother...
당신은 당신과 당신의 형제가 ...
Can you get whatever you want?
원하는 것은 무엇이든 얻을 수 있나요 ?
You have enjoyed all the benefits...
혜택을 다 누리셨네요...
And now you blame your father for ignoring you?
그런데 이제 당신은 당신을 무시한 것에 대해 아버지를 비난합니까?
Who are you to do such a thing?
그런 일을 하는 당신은 누구입니까?
to...
에게...
Of course, you can't blame your father.
물론 아버지를 비난할 수는 없습니다.
But I really want to tell my dad...
하지만 아빠한테는 꼭 말하고 싶은데...
My real feelings right now.
지금 내 진짜 감정.
If you just want to do it...
그냥 하고 싶다고 하면...
My family lives happily...
우리 가족은 행복하게 살고 있어요..
Dad, will you listen to me?
아빠가 내 말 좀 들어줄래?
If you want to prove it...
증명하고 싶다면..
The Father's sacrifice was only for our good...
그 아버지의 희생은 오직 우리의 유익을 위한 것이니라...
I think it would be best for your father to resign.
아버지는 사임하시는 것이 좋을 것 같습니다.
The money I have...
내가 가진 돈은...
With our family wealth...
우리 가족 재산으로...
Enough to open a small perfume shop...
작은 향수 가게를 열 만큼 ...
In a small place...
작은 곳에서..
Without worrying about food or accommodation...
음식 , 숙소 걱정 없이 ...
All our lives.
우리의 모든 삶.
That makes me happier than serving royalty...
왕족을 섬기는 것보다 그게 더 행복한데 ...
Because we are afraid that our lives may be threatened .
우리의 생명이 위협받을까 두렵기 때문입니다 .
Are you happier?
더 행복해?
You only think about your happiness .
당신은 당신의 행복에 대해서만 생각합니다 .
great.
좋아요.
If Dad resigns...
아빠 사임하면..
Who will protect your little brother...
누가 네 동생을 지켜줄지...
Can't you control it later?
나중에는 통제할 수 없나요?
Your father has allowed you to become the son-in-law of the head family...
아버지는 당신 이 종가의 사위가 되는 것을 허락하셨습니다...
Because you can help him...
왜냐하면 당신이 그 사람을 도울 수 있기 때문이죠...
If that person has a problem...
그 사람이 문제가 있으면...
After we leave.
우리가 떠난 후에.
But you only know how to act...
하지만 당신은 행동하는 방법만을 알고 있습니다 ...
Without thinking of others.
남을 생각하지 않고.
to...
에게...
so...
그래서...
I don't want to let go...
놓기 싫다...
Assistant position...
어시스턴트 포지션...
And my brother is just an excuse for my father.
그리고 형은 아버지의 변명일 뿐이에요.
nurse.
유모.
Dad knows this enviable job...
아빠는 이 부러운 직업을 아시죠 ...
Is that a big problem too?
그것도 큰 문제야?
If dad could do anything...
아빠가 뭐든지 할 수 있다면...
To remove a colleague for this position...
이 직위에 대한 동료를 제거하려면 ...
They can do the same to Dad.
그들은 아빠에게도 똑같이 할 수 있어요.
Later, when Dad leaves this place...
나중에 아빠가 이 자리에서 떨어지면 ...
Do you know what awaits our family?
우리 가족을 기다리고 있는 것이 무엇인지 아시나요 ?
With prosperity comes loss .
번영에는 손실도 따릅니다 .
At that time , there was no one in my family...
그땐 우리 가족 중에 아무도 없었는데...
You might miss it.
놓칠 수 있습니다.
If Dad continues to be superstitious...
아빠가 계속 미신을 믿는다면...
With power and wealth...
권력과 부를 가지고...
This will only make our family's situation worse...
그러면 우리 가족의 상황이 더 악화될 뿐입니다 ...
When the time comes.
때가되면.
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Will this end badly for my family?
우리 가족에게 나쁜 결말을 가져올까요 ?
- honey! - father!
- 여보! - 아버지!
- dad. - A rebellious child!
- 아빠. - 반항적인 아이!
Honey, calm down!
여보, 진정하세요!
After raising you for years ...
몇 년 동안 당신을 키운 끝에...
I only get disobedience from you!
나는 당신에게서 불순종을 얻을뿐입니다 !
I really don't want to see you again.
난 정말 당신을 다시 보고 싶지 않아요.
Get out of here!
여기서 나가!
- now! - to!
- 지금! - 에게!
Honey, calm down!
여보, 진정하세요!
Qian, that's it.
퀴안, 바로 그거야.
Kian. fast.
키안. 빠른.
Get your sister out of here.
언니를 여기서 내보내세요.
It seems...
것 같다...
Unable to reach agreement...
합의에 도달하지 못함..
Between us today.
오늘 우리 사이.
If dad insists on being a helper...
아빠가 도우미가 되겠다고 고집한다면...
Please forgive me for disobeying you.
불순종한 것을 용서해주세요.
This is just advice to fathers.
이것은 단지 아버지에게 드리는 조언입니다.
Kian.
키안.
Please take good care of your sister.
언니를 잘 돌봐주세요.
Qian, come back and take care of yourself.
Qian, 돌아와서 몸조심하세요.
- Kian. - Rest! I heard
- 키안. - 쉬어 라! 들었어
Don't come here again.
다시는 여기에 오지 마세요.
Okay, honey.
알았어, 얘야.
relax.
진정하다.
Kian.
키안.
You can't disobey your father.
아빠 말을 거스르면 안 돼요.
Look how angry he is.
그가 얼마나 화가 났는지보세요.
What do you mean, go and apologize?
가서 사과한다는 게 무슨 말이에요?
I think so too...
나도 생각하는데...
Did I do something wrong today?
내가 오늘 뭔가 잘못했나?
I want to live...
나는 살고 싶다...
With power and wealth...
권력과 부를 가지고...
But it's full of fights...
하지만 싸움만 가득하고...
Or can you live peacefully in your village?
아니면 마을에서 평화롭게 살 수 있나요?
Why should we choose?
우리는 왜 선택해야 하는가?
The Father is here, so what have we to fear?
아버지가 여기 계시는데 우리가 무엇을 두려워합니까?
Why should we live...
우리는 왜 살아야 하는가...
In the Village?
빌리지에서?
So, my brother is still used to being from a rich family...
그러니까 형은 아직도 부잣집 나이에 익숙하구나...
And strength...
그리고 힘...
I don't want to be an ordinary person...
평범한 사람이 되고 싶지도 않고...
And do you live a normal life?
그리고 평범한 삶을 살고 있나요?
Life is pretty good now.
지금은 생활이 꽤 좋습니다.
You worry too much.
너는 걱정이 너무 많아.
Kediaman Hua
케디아만 후아
obvious...
분명한...
No one in my family listens to me...
우리 가족 중 누구도 내 말을 듣지 않는다...
Or trust me.
아니면 나를 믿으세요.
let's go.
갑시다.
Kian.
키안.
Tuan.
투안.
Who did that?
누가 그랬나요?
Can I ask you a favor?
부탁드려도 될까요?
There aren't many people who can hit me, right?
나를 때릴 수 있는 사람은 많지 않죠 ?
You are still the Lady of the Bell Residence.
당신은 여전히 ​​종 거주지의 여인입니다 .
Don't let others bother you later.
나중에 다른 사람들이 당신을 괴롭히도록 두지 마십시오 .
If not, you are embarrassing me.
그렇지 않다면 당신은 나를 부끄럽게 만드는 것입니다.
Do you care about me?
당신은 나에 대해 관심이 있습니까?
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
I would like you to know something.
나는 당신이 뭔가를 알고 싶습니다.
- you! - Can you see it now?
- 너! - 이제 보이나요?
If you force me to stay here ...
나한테 계속 여기 머물라고 강요한다면 ...
I can't stand the pain in my eyes...
눈이 아픈 건 참을 수가 없어요 ...
And it's impossible for me to live ...
그리고 나는 살기가 불가능합니다 ...
Be quiet here.
조용히 여기.
I'm just telling the truth.
나는 단지 진실을 말하고 있을 뿐입니다.
Why did you hit me so hard?
왜 그렇게 세게 때렸어요?
Madam, is it true that you want a divorce?
부인, 이혼하고 싶다는 게 사실인가요?
Are you divorced?
이혼했나요?
I want to divorce, but it's not easy.
이혼하고 싶은데 그게 쉽지 않네요.
In the end , if you decide to divorce...
결국 이혼하자고 하면..
It will embarrass Tuan Yelan.
그것은 Tuan Yelan을 당황하게 할 것이다.
He also said he would forget my mistake.
그는 또한 내 실수를 잊을 것이라고 말했습니다.
I was just on the phone with my dad...
방금 아빠랑 통화 중이었는데 ...
Look how I ended up like this .
내가 어떻게 이렇게 됐는지 보세요 .
Then ma'am...
그럼 부인...
Why did you do that to Tuan Ye Lan earlier?
아까 투안예란한테 왜 그랬어요 ?
There is no way to ask for a divorce.
이혼을 요구할 방법이 없습니다 .
So I have no choice but to force him.
그래서 나는 그에게 강요할 수밖에 없습니다.
This is it...
바로 이거 야...
How is your research?
당신의 조사는 어떻습니까?
You don't want me to interfere.
당신은 내가 간섭하는 것을 원하지 않습니다.
But I haven't heard any news from you .
그런데 당신에게서 어떤 소식도 듣지 못했어요 .
I came to tell you this.
나는 이것을 말하려고 왔습니다.
My father just sent me a letter.
아버지가 방금 편지를 보냈어요.
He discovered the perfume formula...
그는 향수 공식을 발견했습니다 ...
Aquilaria scent can be made lower ...
아퀼라리아 향을 더 낮게 만들 수 있는 ...
Real scent.
진짜 향.
expert...
전문가...
Based on decades of perfume experience
수십년의 향수 경험을 바탕으로
Can't tell the difference.
차이점을 알 수 없습니다.
So my father was deceived.
그래서 아버지가 속으신 거죠.
This technology...
이 기술은 ...
It's the same technology...
같은 기술인데..
This is what the Ge family uses.
Ge 가족이 사용하는 것입니다.
After listening to the conversation...
대화를 듣고 나서야 ..
Between you and the owner that day ...
그날 너와 주인 사이에...
I got a clue.
나는 단서를 얻었다.
What you mean is...
네 말 뜻은...
Were the runaway Ge family also involved in the same thing?
도망친 Ge 가족도 같은 일에 연루되었나요?
So why did they imprison your family?
그런데 왜 그들은 당신의 가족을 가두었나요?
I don't know
모르겠어요.
But there's something strange about the man in the middle...
그런데 중간 남자가 뭔가 이상한데...
A person who delivered furniture...
가구배달 하던 사람..
Including...
포함하는...
To our accommodation.
우리 숙소로.
After the family was arrested and imprisoned...
가족이 체포되어 투옥된 후..
He just disappeared.
그는 방금 사라졌습니다.
Whether alive or dead, no one can find him.
살아 있든 죽어 있든 그를 찾을 수 있는 사람은 아무도 없습니다 .
Recently I talked to Hua Qian prostitutes.
최근에 나는 Hua Qian 창녀들과 이야기를 나눴습니다.
This issue is very complex.
이 문제는 매우 복잡합니다.
That person may not be the main character...
그 사람이 주인공이 아닐 수도 있는데...
But he could also be an accomplice.
하지만 공범일 수도 있습니다.
But the Fahrenheit family might be hostile...
하지만 화씨 가문은 적대적일지도...
With the Ge family.
Ge 가족과 함께.
So have you ever thought about it...
그럼 혹시 생각해 본 적 있나요...
Maybe Hua Qian happened to...
어쩌면 Hua Qian이 우연히...
Suggest you a bad broker...
당신에게 나쁜 중개인을 제안하십시오 ...
Does he have anything to do with this?
그 사람은 이 일과 아무 관련이 없나요?
You've never seen him...
당신은 그를 본 적이 없습니다 ...
Deny this...
이것을 부정하다...
Or just look at how he rejects me...
아니면 그 사람이 나를 어떻게 거부하는지 보세요...
When I asked him the truth.
내가 그에게 진실을 물었을 때.
So I understand why you think that.
그래서 나는 당신이 왜 그렇게 생각하는지 이해합니다.
I didn't mean it that way.
그런 뜻은 아니었어요.
It's very difficult for me to research.
제가 조사하는 것은 매우 어렵습니다.
If you can't stand it...
참을 수 없다면...
And I don't want to continue...
그리고 계속하고 싶지 않아요...
I will not force you to help me.
나는 당신에게 나를 도와달라고 강요하지 않을 것입니다.
no.
아니요.
Because this case is unfair...
이 사건은 불공평하니까...
We need to investigate the truth.
진실을 조사해야 해요.
If you need help, you can instruct Nanfeng.
도움이 필요하면 Nanfeng에 지시할 수 있습니다 .
Hua Qian 풀라...
Hua Qian 풀라...
Madam, Madam Hua sent another letter.
부인, 부인 Hua는 또 다른 편지를 보냈습니다.
Set it aside.
옆에 놓으십시오.
approval.
승인.
ma'am.
부인.
It's been a few days ma'am. Mr. Hua wrote a letter to her wife.
며칠이 지났습니다 부인. 화씨는 부인에게 편지를 썼습니다.
Read it first.
먼저 읽어보세요.
He wants me back...
그 사람은 내가 돌아오길 원해...
And I apologize to my father.
그리고 아버지께 사과드립니다.
So it's okay if you don't read it.
그러니 읽지 않아도 괜찮습니다.
Are you not going to talk to that person again ?
그 사람이랑 다시 얘기 안 할 거야 ?
Of course not.
당연히 아니지.
I just want them to know where I am.
나는 단지 그들이 내가 어디에 있는지 알기를 원할 뿐입니다.
Although their views cannot be changed immediately ...
비록 그들의 견해를 즉시 바꿀 수는 없지만 ...
It will affect them.
그것은 그들에게 영향을 미칠 것입니다.
Cik puan, Nanfeng datang.
Cik puan, Nanfeng datang.
Why did he come again?
그 사람은 왜 또 왔나요?
What's the problem this time?
이번에는 무엇이 문제인가?
Let him in.
그를 들여 보내세요.
Hello, madam.
안녕하세요, 부인.
What is that?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Are you having trouble at home?
집에 문제가 있나요?
no.
아니요.
I came to talk to the lady ...
아주머니한테 말씀드리러 왔어요 ...
The feast will be held three days later...
향연은 사흘 후에 열릴 것이라...
And you want your wife to attend with him...
그리고 당신은 부인이 그 사람과 함께 참석하길 원하시죠...
Di Taman species.
디 타만 종.
Who will be there?
거기에는 누가 있을까요?
Directors gathered from all over the country...
전국 각지에서 모인 감독님들..
Wu family and other suppliers...
우 가족 및 기타 공급 업체...
A person who worked with the Zhong family.
Zhong 가족과 함께 일한 사람.
Keluar woo?
켈루아르가 우?
Will that happen in the end?
결국 그렇게 될까요?
Do you have any questions?
질문있으세요?
Why do you want me to attend?
내가 왜 참석하기를 바라나요?
It's a big party.
큰 파티예요.
Of course, you must also attend.
물론 당신도 함께 참석해야 합니다.
Lakaman Bonus
라카만 보너스
you?
너?
Did you come back after so many years ?
그렇게 오랜 세월이 흐른 뒤에야 돌아오셨나요?
I want you to make me something.
나한테 뭔가 만들어 줬으면 좋겠어.
Just curious...
그냥 궁금해서...
Why did you come to see me?
왜 나를 만나러 왔나요?
Looks...
보기에...
you want something from me
당신은 나에게 뭔가를 원하는
Any price is acceptable.
어떤 가격이라도 허용됩니다.
Why do you talk like we are foreigners?
왜 우리가 외국인인 것처럼 말해요 ?
After all, I have been your teacher for several years.
결국 나는 몇 년 동안 당신의 선생님이었습니다.
Are you really a good apprentice?
정말 좋은 견습생인가요?